Guide to the Women's Rights Poster Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Women's rights poster collection
1976-1977
SC0807
Butler, Matilda collector
1 Linear feet
Collection includes images of historic feminist protests and leaders, images of the 1970s women's movement, images of women in non-traditional jobs, Black women leaders, images pertaining to changing sex roles, and a series on women of the American Revolution. Groups and/or publishers represented include Women's Equity Action League, Sex Desegregation Assistance Center of the Southwest (Texas), Documentary Photo Aids, and the U. S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. Collection also includes a set of 8 photographs and a poster of men in the nurturing role published by the Women's Action Alliance (New York).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Matilda Butler earned her MA in communication at Stanford University in 1966 and was on the staff of the Institute for Communication Research at Stanford.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes images of historic feminist protests and leaders, images of the 1970s women's movement, images of women in non-traditional jobs, Black women leaders, images pertaining to changing sex roles, and a series on women of the American Revolution. Groups and/or publishers represented include Women's Equity Action League, Sex Desegregation Assistance Center of the Southwest (Texas), Documentary Photo Aids, and the U. S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. Collection also includes a set of 8 photographs and a poster of men in the nurturing role published by the Women's Action Alliance (New York).
Access Terms
Butler, Matilda collector; Feminism--United States.; Photoprints.; Posters.; Women's rights--United States--Posters.
Collection Contents
- Posters, 1976-1977
  - Federal Laws and Regulations Concerning Sex Discrimination in Educational Institutions, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Our World is Changing (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Men in the Nurturing Role, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Our World is Changing (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Families - choices: learning about changing sex roles, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - What's Wrong With These Pictures? (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Roots - choices: learning about changing sex roles, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - What's Wrong With These Pictures? (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Federal Laws and Regulations Prohibiting Sex Discrimination, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Equal Credit Opportunity Act, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - DPA Pioneers Series (42 photo posters on the Feminist Revolution, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Shirley Chisholm, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - No Stereotyping (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - You Can So Do It (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Union Organizer, Farm Worker, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Barbara Jordan, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Women of the American Revolution (set of 9 painted placards of women in the Revolution including: Catherine Greene, Elizabeth Zane, Martha Washington, etc.), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)